downtoearth.org.in 2019-08-03

# Privacy Policy

Society for Environmental Communications' Down To Earth (DTE) has adopted a set of information management guidelines that serve as the basis for our relationships with our friends, visitors, customers and others interested in environment, development and sustainability issues. These guidelines have been developed with the recognition that Internet technologies are rapidly evolving, and that underlying business models are still not established. Accordingly, guidelines are subject to change. If the changes represent a material departure from our current practices with respect to the use of personal information, the changes will be posted on this page thirty days prior to taking effect.

**Most importantly we understand and appreciate how much you care about how your personal information is used and shared. We take your privacy very seriously.**

**Information gathered and tracked**

Information submitted through all feedback forms on any DTE website is stored in a database. Specifically, we store the name, e-mail address, and demographic information (address, occupation, etc) of the visitors to our website who wish to receive certain free services from DTE, including but not limited to newsletters, e-mail lists, and online discussions. We also use such information to send out occasional promotional materials, including alerts on new publications available for sale. We have clearly marked which information is optional and which is mandatory. 

  As a proactive organisation deeply involved in disseminating research on science, environment, development and sustainability such information is crucial in helping us sustain our advocacy efforts. We guarantee that personal information about users will not be provided to any third party without their consent. We perform statistical analyses of user behaviour in order to measure interest in our newsletters and other services for future content development purposes.

  **E-mail / Mailing list policies**

Using the e-mail addresses provided at registration, we construct mailing lists used for regular newsletters and occasional promotional e-mails. We may contact users regarding account status, changes to the subscriber agreement, and to confirm registration via e-mail. The e-mail addresses that users supply to use this service will not be used for any other purpose without their consent.

  Addresses provided by registered users may occasionally be used for sending promotional materials regarding DTE activities. In addition, the address and other contact details of experts working in various fields are also used in specialised contact directories published by DTE, but only with the express consent of those included in such directories. However you will not be contacted in any other way, nor will your information be offered to a third-party. We do not sell, rent or share our mailing list.If you do not want to receive e-mails from us, please follow the instructions contained in the unwanted e-mail message

**Subscription**

To subscribe to DTE  and access the associated services, you will be required to provide some personal information and accept the terms and conditions applicable. This information may include your username, name, email id, phone number and state of residence. This information will be used at an individual level only to manage your subscription account, and at an aggregate level only to tailor our offerings to our audience. We use third party payment service providers to process the payment of subscription fees. We do not store any user payment data. Our third party payment service providers will be visible to you while making the payment and you may choose the one you prefer out of the options available.

**Data security**

Your account is protected by an encrypted password. We keep it secure, and you must also keep it safe. Our employees may not access your account unless required to do a specific job.

**Opting-out, corrections and cancellations**

Upon request, we will immediately a) Remove user information from our database thereby cancelling that user's registration; b) Correct personal information that a user states is erroneous; or c) Permit a user to "opt out" of further e-mail contact, while still allowing access to the site. To request a correction or cancellation please send us an e-mail addressed to: [dte@cseindia.org](mailto:dte@cseindia.org) with ' **Un-subscribe** ' in the subject.

  **Compliance with legal process / compelled disclosure**

If we are required by law to disclose any information that you have provided to us, we will try and ensure that we give you notice (unless we are prohibited) that a request for your information has been made and give you an opportunity to object. We will send you this notice by email (if you have provided it to us) or by post. If we do not receive a reply we will supply this information, which we are bound to do so by law. 

  **Reservation**

Down To Earth (DTE) reserves the right to change our policy at any time in order to address new issues and reflect changes on our site. By using these services after we post changes, you indicate your acceptance to those changes.

  **Questions?Comments?**  
**Please write to**[dte@cseindia.org](mailto:dte@cseindia.org)
